Timothy Knight

Chaplin, CT

267-234-3403 | timothyknightwriter@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/timothy-knightmoore

CONTENT AND COPY EDITOR

Content and Copy Editor possessing over 15 years of experience in collaborating with classroom teachers and other education professionals in the writing and implementation of academic curricula for many levels of learning across multiple age groups. Confident writer of lesson plans and project maps with a strong eye for editing grammar in both personal and client copy. Helping varied clients find their voices. A language lover and student at heart with formal studies in English, Ancient Greek and Latin and some Spanish as well as personal explorations in French and German.

KEY SKILLS

Level Specific Curriculum Planning | Lesson planning | English Grammar | Latin Grammar | Copy Writing | Copy Editing | Comprehension and Phonics | Project Management | Conflict Resolution | Team Management | Microsoft Office Suite | Google Education Suite | MLA Style | AP Style

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Copy & Content Editor

Timothy Knightwriter, Glenolden, PA and Chaplin, CT

March 2014 – Present

Provide copy editing and content creation services pro bono for various clients.

- Editing email and blog marketing copy.
- Presenting word choice options based on style, format, and historical and cultural linguistic preference.
- Correcting grammar and vocabulary.
- Suggesting thematic and story driven organization and pacing edits.

Latin and Creative Writing Teacher

Moorestown High School and William Allen Middle School, Moorestown, NJ July 2007 – June 2019 Managed critical written and verbal communication skills for approximately 125 students daily. Provided a regular curriculum evaluating students on mastery of Classical Latin language and history as well as creative writing. Established quiz methodology that resulted in a 10% increase in overall quiz scores per student.

- Identified grammar and style issues, working directly with students to identify and then correct their own mistakes.
- Taught critical organization, study skills, time and project management.
- Collaborated with multiple colleagues, departments and buildings while coordinating their varied schedules.
- Met regularly with parents and faculty to identify areas of focus and to support student growth objectives.
- Utilized scheduled and pop quizzes to encourage conscious content editing and accuracy under pressure.
- Co-advisor in the Interact Club, managing fundraising events to generate donations to various causes.

Latin Teacher

Timber Creek High School, Blackwood, NJ

July 2006 - June 2007

Became the sole instructor at this high school, one of three in the Black Horse Pike Regional school district's program.

- Complied with state mandated core content standards in conjunction with district curriculum.
- Authored new review materials to fill in and reinforce students' knowledge gaps.
- Increased Latin level II and III course enrollment for the following year.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Part-Time Latin Instructor

Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX

August 2004 - May 2006

Taught Undergraduate Latin and a Greek and Latin Roots course for future doctors and lawyers.

- Consulted with supervisors to discuss and develop pedagogical philosophy.
- Developed syllabi with an eye for content and pacing.
- Authoring, proctoring, and grading assessments for undergraduate students.
- Holding office hours to provide personalized assistance for undergraduate students.

Latin Teacher's Assistant

Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX

August 2004 - May 2006

Assistant to two professors in the Classical Language and Literature Department.

- Graded assessments.
- Held office hours for undergraduate student assistance.
- Digitized slides for professors.

EDUCATION

Master of Arts in Classical Studies, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX

Bachelor of Arts in English & Classical Studies, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

CERTIFICATIONS

Dual NJ Standard Teacher's Certificate – Latin and English